<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alfred Nutile</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/</link><description>Recent content on Alfred Nutile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 06:32:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alfrednutile.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 06:32:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/projects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Billing and Other Workflow Details</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/billing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/billing/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The page will cover how billing works and the different ways I can work with you to create features for your business.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hourly-rates">Hourly Rates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We will discuss my hourly rate before starting the work. Once agreed, we can then talk about feature(s) that the business would like me to build or assist in building. I try to avoid &lt;strong>Waterfall&lt;/strong> projects &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> or digging too deep into feature months down the roadmap since often goals change, and that time is then not a good use of budget or time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some companies need a &lt;strong>Fix Bid&lt;/strong> workflow, and I will talk about this shortly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any work will start with a clear sense of scope from me. For example, you may have a goal of delivering feature CSV upload. So first, I will give you a sense of the overall cost &lt;strong>range&lt;/strong> of to complete. And then, I will also break up the work into &amp;ldquo;small batches&amp;rdquo; to get a sense of daily goals. Then due to the billing cadence and my &amp;ldquo;daily check-in model&amp;rdquo; (more on that in a moment), you will see progress along the way and have an ongoing reality check. This cadence allows you to pivot at any time in the feature build. And also to know that we are building the right feature at the right speed.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;the principle of small batches. Functional specialists, especially those steeped in waterfall or stage-gate development, have been trained to work in extremely large batches. This causes even good ideas to get bogged down by waste. By making the batch size small, the sandbox method allows teams to make cheap mistakes quickly and start learning. As we&amp;rsquo;ll see below, these small initial experiments can demonstrate that a team has a viable new business that can be integrated back into the parent company. - Ries, Eric. The Lean Startup: How Today&amp;rsquo;s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses (p. 264).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="billing-cadence">Billing Cadence&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The cadence is every 15 days I will send an invoice with a detailed hourly list of the work done and the total for that two weeks. The payment cycle is NET 15. You can see this daily on the billing website, more on that shortly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This cadence has apparent advantages for me but also for you, as seen in the quote above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the work I do for you will always take place in &amp;ldquo;small batches&amp;rdquo;. No matter how big the feature you are having me work on, I will break down the work into 1-3 days chunks. In that period, I will deliver results to &lt;strong>production&lt;/strong> daily so you will see progress, and both you and I will know how the feature is going and pivot, as needed before too much time, is invested.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-check-in">Daily Check-In&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As noted above, I will email or chat (Slack, Teams etc) with a list of goals for the day. Typically 1-2 Pull Requests (sending code to the code storage system and then production) will be my goal. This workflow represents fully functional parts of the overall feature. Of course, even after I deploy it to production, some of this will not be seen by you, the user, but knowing it is there helps you know progress is clearly being made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tracking-progress">Tracking Progress&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have a ticket system, I can put all the feature(s) broken into &amp;ldquo;small batches&amp;rdquo;. For example, a feature that will take me approximately four days of work will end up being no less than 8 &amp;ldquo;tickets.&amp;rdquo; This pace allows me to continue working per the standards seen in the State of DevOps and, hopefully the &lt;strong>Elite&lt;/strong> levels seen there. If you do not have a system and are using GitHub, we can use the system provided by GitHub. Read more about &amp;ldquo;Elite Performance&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href="https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/state-of-devops-2019.pdf">here&lt;/a> page 18 shows the chart.&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://alfrednutile.info/images/elite.png" width="800" class="center">
&lt;h2 id="fixed-bid">Fixed Bid&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If a fixed bid is required and creating an accurate bid required thirty or more minutes of my time, then that time will be billed at my hourly rate. The will be billable time even if the work is not ever approved to be worked on. You will get a clear breakdown of each item using a formula from the &amp;ldquo;Agile Estimating and Planning&amp;rdquo; you can read more about it on my Medium post &lt;a href="https://alnutile.medium.com/we-code-in-the-context-of-our-quoting-dab391fe0881">We Code in the Context of our Quoting&lt;/a>. By the end of the quote, I will hand you an itemized spreadsheet as seen above so you can see where the time is going to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the bid is approved, then payments will happen in 2-3 steps. Depending on the size, the payment will be 1/3 to start the project, 1/3 halfway through completion, and 1/3 on delivery. The 1/3 to start is &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> NET 15 but is paid before starting. From there, the halfway point is NET 7, and the final invoice is NET 15.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="feature-owners">Feature Owners&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In working on a feature, I will need a point person or persons to know I am delivering the right feature. With this, I expect daily communications in &lt;strong>Slack&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Teams&lt;/strong> etc in case I get stuck or need them to review a delivered part of the feature. Most weeks will start with a rundown on what I am working on to ensure it is still a priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a dedicated feature owner is key. Getting paid is &lt;strong>nice&lt;/strong> building the right thing that someone will use is essential to me as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="billing-system">Billing System&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You will interact with the system &lt;a href="https://alfrednutile.invoice.services/client/login">Client Portal&lt;/a>. So you can easily pay online. You will receive an email with your username and password. However, you can just reset it &lt;a href="https://alfrednutile.invoice.services/client/login">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall_model">Waterfall&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/state-of-devops-2019.pdf">State of DevOps Report&lt;/a> &lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description>
biz</item></channel></rss>