<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Alfred Nutile</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Alfred Nutile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 14:32:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alfrednutile.info/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CI - GitHub Actions and Laravel (Part 1 of 3)</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/ci_cd_part_one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 14:32:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/ci_cd_part_one/</guid><description>The point is GitHub Actions should be revolutionizing your team&amp;rsquo;s workflows; if it is not, you are missing something important.
This first post is part one of three. In this series I will cover the following topics.
PT 1 CI - Simple Continuous Integration using GitHub Actions PT 2 CD - Simple Continuous Deployment using GitHub Actions PT 3 Security - Shifting Left on Security Please keep in mind that the repository and code below I am sharing is not an end product and will evolve.</description></item><item><title>Being on Offense When it Comes to Day to Day Scheduling</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/scheduling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/scheduling/</guid><description>How do we go on the &amp;ldquo;offensive&amp;rdquo; leaving behind what has only become a &amp;ldquo;defensive&amp;rdquo; effort to save our day from becoming unproductive? Leaving us at the end of the day feeling like we need to make up some time after work or the weekend
This post will be a look at how to manage your time in the midst of what can seem to be endless distractions and too many things needing to be done at once.</description></item><item><title>Ongoing: Links and Notes About DevOps Transformation Using the Accelerate Data and Strategies</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/sod/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/sod/</guid><description>Next time I needed this info, I just wanted to make sure that I have the links I need concerning the Accelerate book and Software Delivery Performance. So I will use this page to continue to add info about these resources.
The links below really are all related as the authors work together in the different books, videos and research papers.
TL;DR The most critical link State of DevOps Reports</description></item><item><title>CentOS or RedHat and Laravel</title><link>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/167/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alfrednutile.info/posts/167/</guid><description>Got Ideas from here An Ansible Tutorial
Just wrapped up setting up two RedHat servers (version 7) and one CentOS Virtual box so I could deploy a Laravel site.
Code is here
Thanks to Ansible it was not as bad as it could have been.
I am not an ansible expert just getting into it as we need to do this more. What these scripts will do is
Setup a CentOS Vagrant box Setup a Server for Laravel and Queues SupervisorD Setup up SSHD to be key based only you can remove this Setup Cron to run scheduler Setup SSL if you make the keys for this Redirect to https for site Local VM Step one is to install Ansible on your Mac and then vim /etc/ansible/hosts</description></item></channel></rss>