<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rails on Alfred Nutile</title><link>https://alnutile.github.io/tags/rails/</link><description>Recent content in rails on Alfred Nutile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alnutile.github.io/tags/rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Heroku in Heroku</title><link>https://alnutile.github.io/posts/30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alnutile.github.io/posts/30/</guid><description>As I build out these sites I had to run heroku commands on heroku since the admin site needs to setup Domains and Subdomain on each new site. I was glad they had the&amp;nbsp;https://github.com/heroku/heroku.rb&amp;nbsp;gem&amp;nbsp;that made it possible to make an interface for administrators to add domains and subdomains to their heroku site.&amp;nbsp;
In my controller I included the heroku-api as the node on the github page.
After that, on an update or a create I check if the domain exists.</description></item><item><title>HerokuApps and Multiple Domains</title><link>https://alnutile.github.io/posts/27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alnutile.github.io/posts/27/</guid><description>There are some great docs online for figuring out how to setup heroku domains.
https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/custom-domains as well as others.
The feature I had to get setup was that for every new herokuapp I spun up under my account/clients account it had to make a sub-domain under that SaaS owners zone/domain.
For example the owner wanted all of these apps to show up under freesurvey.com (not really but just an example url)&amp;nbsp;so each one they spun up would be, for example yoursite.</description></item><item><title>Going Angular.js</title><link>https://alnutile.github.io/posts/2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alnutile.github.io/posts/2/</guid><description>Going Angular
Took some time to rewrite my drupal/bootstrap site into Angular.js and slim php.
Using slim and a seed project I quickly had a rest api to get the different content types, Blog, Page etc.
I am using the Page content type to make other dynamic parts to the site like Footer and Header.
After a quick migration from drupal to a more basic MySQL db layout (soon mongodb?</description></item></channel></rss>